

Content Designer | Web Designer | Creative Expert

Number: 07751110706

Email: <u>TaihgMcDonagh@outlook.com</u> LinkedIn: Uk.linkedin.com/in/taihg

GitHub: github.com/taihg

Website: Taihg.com

Professional Profile

A multi-skilled Content Designer located in the West Midlands. I specialise in Front-End Web Design & Content Creation. I have an in-depth understanding of the Adobe Creative Cloud (including Photoshop and Premiere Pro).

I have extensive experience working with HTML5, CSS3 & Bootstrap. Additionally, I possess a thorough knowledge of Content Management Systems including the use of applications such as Shopify & WordPress.

Education and Qualifications

BSc Business Computing The University of Northampton (2016 - 2019)

(Web Design) Final year modules include:

Business Intelligence

Grade: 2:1 Computing Dissertation

Cybersecurity and Cryptography

IT Project Management Media Technology

Level 3 Computing

Diploma

<u>Bedford College</u> (2014 - 2016) **Final year modules include:**

Information Systems

Grade: Distinction Communication Technologies

IT Technical Support

IT Systems Troubleshooting & Repair Client-Side Customisation of Web Pages

Spreadsheet Modelling

Professional Experience

2020 - Present Lead Content Designer: LIVEWIRE Telecom Limited, UK

- Comfort coding in HTML5, CSS3 & Bootstrap in a text editor and with editing text embedded in developer code
- Sold Background using Content Management Systems such as Shopify & WordPress
- In depth portfolio of successful product launches with some of the biggest names in the tech industry including Huawei, Xiaomi, realme, Oppo, Vivo, Honor, Mara etc.
- · Manage the content team and supervised all graphic materials in order to ensure quality and accuracy of the design
- Led in the design, development and implementation of content for multiple websites and media channels including YouTube, Modem.co.uk, LW.co.uk & eFones.com

2019 – 2020 Junior Front-End Designer: LIVEWIRE Telecom Limited, UK

- Designed numerous graphics (logos, brochures, infographics, presentations, product listings, social media campaigns and advertisements)
- Managed multiple projects under tight time constraints to meet the needs of clients & partners
- Recommended and consulted with clients & partners on the most appropriate design techniques for a given task
- Liaised with outsourced Web Developers & Marketing teams to ensure all content id on brand suitable for the businesses needs

Programming Languages, Technologies & Skills

- ➤ HTML5
- ➤ CCS3
- Bootstrap
- ▶ PHI
- WordPress
- Shopify
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Premiere Pro
- Adobe Illustrator
- Ableton Live
- Omnisend

- MySQL
- Oracle
- Microsoft Word
- Microsoft PowerPoint
- Microsoft Excel

Personal Details

Interests include:

When I am not doing something creative on a computer, I enjoy writing & recording music, I am an exgymnast and an avid trampolinist. I enjoy spending time with friends & family and frequently train at the gym. I venture outside whenever possible and you can often find me in the middle of a forest camping, scaling a cliff or somewhere in-between.

I discovered my creative side when I started making YouTube background's and logos on an old Dell Dimension 4700 on Photoshop CS2, and that creative flair evolved into a love of Content Design as I am now fully immersed into the world of Web Design & Content Creation.

References

Liz Coulter-smith

Senior Lecturer
The University of Northampton
<u>Liz-coulter-smith@mynorthampton.ac.uk</u>

Julia Vernon

Senior Lecturer
The University of Northampton
Julia.vernon@mynorthampton.ac.uk